Shcherbak Aleksei | PHP Developer

Creative PHP (Laravel, Symfony) Developer with 4+ years of strong experience in backend (PHP, Laravel, Symfony, C#, .NET) and frontend (Vue, React, jQuery), GOF Design Patterns & OOP areas with willingness to learn new technologies and languages.

CONTACTS

- Phone: +7-911-911-4396
- Email: aleksej.shherbak@yandex.ru
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksej-shherbak-538914165/

KEY SKILLS

Back End:

- PHP: 5, 7, 8, Laravel, Lumen, Symfony
- C# (as an additional language)

Front End:

- Vue (stronger), CSS, HTML, React (familiar)
- JavaScript, ES6, REST
- · jQuery, Bootstrap

Databases and storages:

- MySQL
- Postgres
- Redis
- ArangoDb (familiar)

Testing:

PHPUnit, TDD

DevOps:

• Familiar with Gitlab CI, Jenkins, Github actions, Azure devops

Additional instruments and skils:

• Git, Rest, xDebug, Docker / docker-compose, GoF Design Patterns, OOP

WORK HISTORY

Waveaccess, Backend Developer, May 2022 - till now

https://www.wave-access.com

- · Communication with the customer.
- Creating a sprint backlog.
- Estimating of tasks.
- Fullstack development using React, jQuery and Symfony.
- · Coordination with colleagues from different offices in different countries (Denmakr, Lithuania)

Quantum Art, Backend Developer, September 2020 - May 2022

https://quantumart.ru

- Assessing, gathering and validation project requirements using Agile & Scrum principles related to the critical parts of a big telecom operator's website resulting in estimation of Level of effort and required working hours.
- Developing new and customization of the existing features (backend 80%, frontend 20%) for the high-volume telecom operator website.
- · Documenting implemented features.

PushApp, Backend Developer, Fullstack Developer, August 2018 — June 2020

https://pushapp.ru

- Maintaining newly developed and legacy systems critical internal web application utilizing PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, JavaScript and ES6, Vue.JS, jQuery.
- Designing new databases and data schemas for the business-critical online service improving data integrity and execution efficiency.
- Creating new web applications from scratch.
- Full Stack development of the high-volume analytical-facing web application applying knowledge of Vue/Vuex and Laravel.
- Performance tunning of the legacy web applications.
- Mentoring and couching newly hired team members.

Chinese Tour Operator Qiankun, Laravel Developer, June 2018 — August 2018

· Creating internal business management system from scratch using Laravel and PHP.

Blackidea, Fullstack Developer, December 2017 – June 2018

- Full Stack development of the high-volume eCommerce website using PHP and Bitrix framework.
- Developing web applications from scratch using the company's own architecture PHP boilerplate.

Miiix (smart eShop catalog), Backend Developer, December 2016 — December 2017

• Parsing and scraping web pages using php and regexp.

Binardy web studio, Fullstack Developer, June 2015 — December 2016

• Creating and supporting internet shops using PHP.

Seventest, Backend Developer (intern), Backend Developer, February 2015 — June 2015

http://seventest.ru/

• Support legacy web-application using LAMP stack and Drupal 6.

PROJECTS

- https://www.apvkvik.dk (creating new features according to customer's demands using Symfony)
- https://payforinstall.ru (maintains critical features using Codeigniter)
- https://new.rodovoederevo.ru (implementing different backend features and background tasks using .NET Core 3.1 and C#)
- https://mts.ru (Maintaining legacy parts of the website, creating new features according to business demands)
- https://skylink.ru (Support and customization of the existing features)

EDUCATION

St. Petersburg State University of Telecommunications named after Prof. M.A. Bonch-Bruevich, 2018

MY STRENGTHS

I do not shift my job to someone else. If I have a problem, and I can't solve it, and it's clear that my colleagues is unlikely to answer me right away, I'd better go to Stackoverflow and ask. In addition to programming, I like music, play guitar in a band. I try to develop comprehensively and not be a "troglodyte", shielded from the whole world by a wall of monitors.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- English language: B2
- Ready to relocation